# VASANTHA KUMAR V

# **ANALYST**

(+91) 9965504865 kvasu023@yahoo.com

## **KEY SKILLS**

- Statistical Analysis
- Data Modelling
- Client Management

# SKILLS / TOOLS

- Python(DS Libraries), R
- SQL MySQL, PROC SQL
- Big Query, Redash
- T BI, Tableau, seaborn
- Advanced Excel, PPT
- ML Models
- Github, Redshift (AWS)
- Googling, Stackoverflow

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **BE - ELECTRONICS & INSTRUMENTATION**

Anna University - MIT | 2015 - 2019 | 88% Chennai, IN

### **HSC - COMPUTER SCIENCE**

Hilton Matric School | 2013 - 2015 | 96% Tenkasi, IN

# **PUBLIC PROFILE**

<u>LinkedIn</u> <u>Hackerrank</u> <u>Github</u>

### CONTACT

+91 9965504865 kvasu023@yahoo.com Chennai, TN, India

# **PROFILE**

Analyst with 2 years of experience in product and advanced analytics with deep expertise in creating machine learning pipelines, designing and implementing analytics solutions across CPG and Pricing domain). Excellent understanding of various statistical techniques, tools and programming languages.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### ANALYST - DELIVERY EXPERIENCE IMPROVEMENT

Dunzo Pvt Ltd | Nov 2021 - Present

- Creating and working on methodologies to reduce User CR from 4.5% to 3.5%.
- Analyzing product metrics and updating key findings to stakeholders periodically.
- Involved in SO% to retention% coupler design.

#### **SENIOR ANALYST - PRICING ENGINE DEVELOPMENT**

Tiger Analytics | Jun 2021 - Oct 2021

- Delivered Price recommendation engine for a food client on Store X Product X Date level by building HB Models over sales and conjoint data to get increased customer engagement.
- Pivoted sales projection increased by 11% in net revenue.

### **ANALYST - PROMOTION ENGINE DEVELOPMENT**

Tiger Analytics | Jan 2020 - Jan 2021

- Built national and region specific promotion recommendation engine for a food client to attract more new customers.
- Improved the short and long term client engagement with the help of precise promotional suggestions with hybrid model techniques.
- Boosted sales spike by 57% with recommended promos and expanded 9% new customers engagement ratio.

## **ANALYST - SALES ANOMALY IDENTIFICATION**

Tiger Analytics | Aug 2019 - Jan 2020

- Showcased sales anomalies performed by marketing people to push the target for a largest wine and spirits distributor by inspecting sales curve in descriptive & clustering methods.
- Projected boosting of sales by 20 Million USD with an advent of addressing the issue.

# **PROJECTS**

### **SELF DRIVING CAR PROTOTYPE**

Anna University - MIT | Jul 2017 - Mar 2018

- Developed an prototype of automated car with the assistance of Camera, UV Sensors, Raspberry Pi 3b and actuators.
- Tools Used Python, OpenCV, Sklearn.

# FLOW DETECTION USING IMAGE PROCESSING TECHNIQUE

Anna University - MIT | Dec 2018 - Apr 2019

- Designed a liquid flow measurement device using camera by Vortex shedding principle inside a glass tube.
- Improved the accuracy from 31 to 84% by fine tuning the model and the system.